<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<doxygen xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="compound.xsd" version="1.9.3" xml:lang="en-US">
  <compounddef id="build-a-discord-bot-windows-visual-studio" kind="page">
    <compoundname>build-a-discord-bot-windows-visual-studio</compoundname>
    <title>Building a discord bot in Windows using Visual Studio</title>
    <briefdescription>
    </briefdescription>
    <detaileddescription>
<para>To create a basic bot using <bold>Visual Studio 2019</bold> or <bold>Visual Studio 2022</bold>, follow the steps below to create a <emphasis>working skeleton project you can build upon</emphasis>.</para>
<para><orderedlist>
<listitem><para>Make sure you have Visual Studio 2019 or 2022. Community, Professional or Enterprise work fine. These instructions are not for Visual Studio Code. You can <ulink url="https://visualstudio.microsoft.com/downloads/">download the correct version here</ulink>. Note that older versions of Visual Studio will not work as they do not support enough of the C++17 standard.</para>
</listitem><listitem><para>Clone the <ulink url="https://github.com/brainboxdotcc/windows-bot-template/">template project</ulink>. Be sure to clone the entire project and not just copy and paste the cpp file.</para>
</listitem><listitem><para>Double click on the MyBot.sln file in the folder you just cloned <image type="html" name="vsproj_1.png"></image>
</para>
</listitem><listitem><para>Add your bot token (see <ref refid="creating-a-bot-application" kindref="compound">Creating a Bot Token</ref>) and guild ID to the example program <image type="html" name="vsproj_2.png"></image>
</para>
</listitem><listitem><para>Click &quot;Local windows debugger&quot; to compile and run your bot! <image type="html" name="vsproj_3.png"></image>
</para>
</listitem><listitem><para>Observe the build output. There may be warnings, but so long as the build output ends with &quot;1 succeeded&quot; then the process has worked. You may now run your bot! <image type="html" name="vsproj_14.png"></image>
</para>
</listitem></orderedlist>
</para>
<sect2 id="build-a-discord-bot-windows-visual-studio_1autotoc_md110">
<title>Troubleshooting</title>
<para><itemizedlist>
<listitem><para>If you get an error that a dll is missing (e.g. <computeroutput>dpp.dll</computeroutput> or <computeroutput>opus.dll</computeroutput>) when starting your bot, then simply copy all dlls from the <bold>bin</bold> directory of where you extracted the DPP zip file to, into the same directory where your bot&apos;s executable is. You only need to do this once. There should be several of these dll files: <computeroutput>dpp.dll</computeroutput>, <computeroutput>zlib.dll</computeroutput>, <computeroutput>openssl.dll</computeroutput> and <computeroutput>libcrypto.dll</computeroutput> (or similarly named SSL related files), <computeroutput>libsodium.dll</computeroutput> and <computeroutput>opus.dll</computeroutput>. Note the template project does this for you, so you should never encounter this issue.</para>
</listitem><listitem><para>Stuck? You can find us on the <ulink url="https://discord.gg/dpp">official discord server</ulink> - ask away! We don&apos;t bite! </para>
</listitem></itemizedlist>
</para>
</sect2>
    </detaileddescription>
    <location file="docpages/make_a_bot/windows_vs.md"/>
  </compounddef>
</doxygen>
