<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<doxygen xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="compound.xsd" version="1.9.3" xml:lang="en-US">
  <compounddef id="governance" kind="page">
    <compoundname>governance</compoundname>
    <title>Governance and Project Development Structure</title>
    <briefdescription>
    </briefdescription>
    <detaileddescription>
<para>The D++ Project was originally created by Craig Edwards, A.K.A. @brain on Discord.</para>
<sect2 id="governance_1autotoc_md72">
<title>Governance</title>
<para>@brain steers the project, but in effect the project is entirely built upon the contributions of others via pull requests and feedback. For most decisions and most changes, control is ceded to whoever is creating a feature or change, with oversight given to make sure only that the code is stable and scalable and does not operate in a way counter-intuitive to the design of the library.</para>
</sect2>
<sect2 id="governance_1autotoc_md73">
<title>Project Maintainers</title>
<para>Other maintainers with access to merge pull requests (those with the <computeroutput>@PR Review</computeroutput> role on the discord) have access to and responsibility for checking pull requests sent in by contributors and may request additional changes to keep the pulls aligned with the project goals. These members of the D++ team may and do also merge pull requests at their discretion.</para>
</sect2>
<sect2 id="governance_1autotoc_md74">
<title>Decision Making</title>
<para>For most decisions, these are discussed in our <computeroutput>#library-development</computeroutput> channel on Discord. This channel is public for all to view but only contributors may comment. This helps keep the chat clean of discussion that may derail development topics.</para>
</sect2>
<sect2 id="governance_1autotoc_md75">
<title>Contingency</title>
<para><emphasis>In the case of any unforseen disaster such as death of the project leader, control over domain (the only part of the project which has a direct cost attached) would pass to his next of kin who would arrange for transfer to a pre-arranged trusted third party who would adminisrate the domain going forward. Everything else relating to D++ is hosted on GitHub and would continue as normal.</emphasis> </para>
</sect2>
    </detaileddescription>
    <location file="docpages/advanced_reference/governance.md"/>
  </compounddef>
</doxygen>
