<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<doxygen xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="compound.xsd" version="1.9.3" xml:lang="en-US">
  <compounddef id="md_docpages_02_disdppgloss" kind="page">
    <compoundname>md_docpages_02_disdppgloss</compoundname>
    <title>A Glossary of Common Discord Terms</title>
    <briefdescription>
    </briefdescription>
    <detaileddescription>
<para>This is a list of terms that you should know if you want to use D++ (or any other discord library). These terms are not D++ specific, and are commonly used throughout most of the Discord developer community. This list, with a few exceptions, <emphasis><bold>is discord specific</bold></emphasis>, that is to say that this is not a explanation of commonly used C++ terms, it is for people who are not familiar with the terminology of the discord API and libraries themselves.</para>
<sect3 id="md_docpages_02_disdppgloss_1autotoc_md31">
<title>Glossary</title>
<para>Listed in alphabetical order, with terms in bold, here are the basics on...</para>
<para><orderedlist>
<listitem><para><bold>Action row</bold>: A collection of up to five <bold>components</bold> which is attached to a message.</para>
</listitem><listitem><para><bold>Audit log</bold>: A log of <bold>events</bold> that have happened in a <bold>guild</bold>.</para>
</listitem><listitem><para><bold>Auto mod</bold>: Discord&apos;s low-code solution to moderation. However, it is very limited in scope.</para>
</listitem><listitem><para><bold>Badge</bold>: A decoration on someone&apos;s profile showing certain things about them, such as if they have nitro, if they are a discord developer, etc.</para>
</listitem><listitem><para><bold>Bot token</bold>: A secret string of characters that is used as a &quot;login&quot; to your bot. If you lose it or it gets leaked you will have to get a new one from the discord developer portal, so be sure to keep it in a place that is both secure and where you won&apos;t forget it.</para>
</listitem><listitem><para><bold>Button</bold>: A <bold>component</bold> on a message that can be styled that sends an <bold>event</bold> when clicked on by a user.</para>
</listitem><listitem><para><bold>Cache</bold>: A type of storage efficient for things like messages.</para>
</listitem><listitem><para><bold>Callback</bold>: While not strictly related to discord, it is used a LOT in D++. A callback is when a function is passed to another function, sort of like how you might give someone a telephone number (you give them the means to do some sort of interaction rather than asking them how to interact), which is used to handle responses to <bold>events</bold>.</para>
</listitem><listitem><para><bold>Cluster</bold>: A singular bot application, which is composed of one or more <bold>shards</bold>, a <bold>cluster</bold> is the center of bot development.</para>
</listitem><listitem><para>**(Slash) command**: The primary way a user interacts with a bot. It is a command sent to the bot with <bold>parameters</bold> (which may be optional) and is initiated by staring a message with <computeroutput>/</computeroutput>.</para>
</listitem><listitem><para><bold>Component</bold>: A component is anything that can appear in a bot&apos;s message besides text, such as <bold>buttons</bold> and <bold>select menus</bold>.</para>
</listitem><listitem><para><bold>Drop down/Select menu</bold>: A <bold>component</bold> of a message that upon being clicked drops down and allows the user to select an option.</para>
</listitem><listitem><para><bold>Embeds</bold>: A widget attached to a message which can contain multiple fields of texts, an image, and much more information.</para>
</listitem><listitem><para><bold>Ephemeral</bold>: A message only visible to the user being replied to.</para>
</listitem><listitem><para><bold>Event</bold>: Something that a Discord bot can respond to, such as a message being sent, a <bold>button</bold> being clicked, or an option being selected, among others.</para>
</listitem><listitem><para><bold>Guild</bold>: What the Discord API (and most libraries for it) call a server.</para>
</listitem><listitem><para><bold>Intents</bold>: The right for a bot to receive certain data from the Discord API.</para>
</listitem><listitem><para><bold>Interaction</bold>: A object that contains information about whenever a user interacts with a application, such as sending a message or clicking a button. It is the main part of an <bold>event</bold> that will be accessed in an application.</para>
</listitem><listitem><para><bold>Modal</bold>: A pop up form that contains text that can be sent by a bot.</para>
</listitem><listitem><para><bold><ref refid="clusters-shards-guilds" kindref="compound">Shards</ref></bold>: A shard manages part of the workload of your Discord application</para>
</listitem><listitem><para><bold>Snowflake</bold>: An unsigned 64 bit integer (it can represent anything from 0 to 2^64-1) that is used by discord to identify basically everything, including but not limited to, <bold>guilds</bold>, users, messages, and much more.</para>
</listitem><listitem><para><bold>Subcommands</bold>: A command which is derived from a different command, such as a bot that allows a person to get statistics for discord might have a <computeroutput>stats guild</computeroutput> command and a <computeroutput>stats global</computeroutput> command, both of which are <bold>subcommands</bold> of <computeroutput>stats</computeroutput>. </para>
</listitem></orderedlist>
</para>
</sect3>
    </detaileddescription>
    <location file="docpages/02_disdppgloss.md"/>
  </compounddef>
</doxygen>
